

 $\times$ 

vishakha.boni@gmail.com

T +91-8800884206

Q Curanon

Gurgaon, India

in

linkedin.com/in/vishakha-boni-71941b164

## **SKILLS**

- Profound knowledge of Political Science.
- > Excellent communication and written skills
- ➤ Ability to plan, collect material and deliver the
- ➤ Using the blended and integrated teaching- learning strategies in class

## **LANGUAGES**

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Bengali

Limited Working Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Painting

Traveling

Music

Dance

## Vishakha Boni

Social Science Teacher

Educator with 8 years of experience in high school teaching from grades 8-12. Adaptable professional with experience in proven knowledge of classroom management, course design and curriculum development. An enthusiastic educator who understands for students to gain physical skills and confidence for their all-round development to succeed. Looking to contribute my knowledge and skills in your institution.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## TGT Social Science/PGT Political Science Birla Vidya Niketan

07/2022 - Present

Key Responsibilities:

- □ Develop lesson plans and broad plans and teach 10-11 grade students.
- □ Modify curriculum and teaching style to accommodate diverse learners.
- Provided a range of instructional management and assessment strategies to meet the different needs of students for Board Classes which led to outstanding board results for academic years.
- Heading the Examination Department of the school and shouldering the responsibility of a Class Teacher for Board Classes
- Incorporate engaging and integrated teaching learning methods to enhance students' interest in Social Science.
- Presented various ideas on blended learning methods during cross campus teaching.
- Collaborated with colleagues across content areas and grade levels and created quarterly progress reports and individual development plans to ensure students' success while having an active open communication channel with parents.

#### Accolades/ Recognition:

Received various testimonials from parents on students' success, won multiple awards like Teacher Par Excellence Award, Best Employee Award, Best Class Award. In addition, received many positive feedback from Management and Principal for my efforts.

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

## Global Indian International School (04/2019 -07/2022)

Received various testimonials from parents on students' success, won multiple awards like Teacher Par Excellence Award, Best Employee Award, Best Class Award. In addition, received many positive feedback from Management and Principal formy efforts

#### East Point School (04/2017 - 04/2019)

Responsible for lesson planning and raising student achievement levels. Encouraging students for development of academic and social- emotional skills.

Lady Irwin School (07/2015 - 03/2017)

Teaching senior secondary classes (11th and 12th) and creating a record for the best board results in Political Science.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Double Masters in Political Science** IGNOU

Bachelors of Education (B.Ed) Maharishi Dayanand University

**CTET** CBSE

Bachelors of Honours, Political Science University of Delhi